Guide to the Frederick Morrison Babcock Publications, 1941-1973.
Babcock, Frederick Morrison Publications, 1941-1973.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Frederick Morrison Babcock publications, 1941-1973
4087
Frederick Morrison Babcock
3 cubic ft.
Publications, including land valuations, estimates, reports and development studies.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications, including land valuations, estimates, reports and development studies by Frederick Morrison Babcock. Areas represented in these studies are located in Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Maryland, Minnesota, Missouri, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Nevada, New Mexico, Pennsylvania, Virginia and Washington, D.C.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Frederick Morrison Babcock (1898-1983) and his brother Henry Babcock were affiliated with their father's real estate appraisal firm, William H. Babcock and Sons.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications, including land valuations, estimates, reports and development studies by Frederick Morrison Babcock. Areas represented in these studies are located in Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Maryland, Minnesota, Missouri, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Nevada, New Mexico, Pennsylvania, Virginia and Washington, D.C.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Babcock, Frederick Morrison.; Babcock, Henry Andrews, 1891-; Babcock, William H.; William H. Babcock and Sons.
Subjects:
City planning.; Land use--Planning.; Real estate development.; Real property--Valuation.; Real property surveys.; Real property--Illinois.; Real property--Indiana.; Real property--Iowa.; Real property--Kansas.; Real property--Maryland.; Real property--Minnesota.; Real property--Missouri.; Real property--Nevada.; Real property--New Jersey.; Real property--New Mexico.; Real property--New York (State); Real property--North Carolina.; Real property--Pennsylvania.; Real property--Virginia.; Real property--Washington (D.C.); Real estate appraisers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Related collection: William H. Babcock and Sons. Records. University of Wyoming, Archive of Contemporary History.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. New Jersey
  - Jersey City
    - Valuation. Re-Use Parcel #1, Holland Tunnel Urban Renewal Project, July 13, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Valuations. Re-Use Parcel #2, Holland Tunnel Urban Renewal Project, October 11, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Columbus Bridge Plaza West Project, Jersey City, August 1, 1968 (Box 1)
  - West Orange
    - Valuations. Disposition Parcels, Thomas A. Edison Urban Renewal Project, West Orange., February 3, 1967 (Box 1)
  - West New York
    - Valuations, Disposition Tracts, Revised Plan Boulevard East Urban Renewal Project., June 25, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Disposition Tracts. Revised Plan Boulevard East Urban Renewal Project., December 7, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Trenton
    - Valuations, Re-Use Parcels 2, 3, & 5, John Fitch Way #3 Urban Renewal Project., August 2, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Disposition Plans, Trenton Mall, City Center Urban Renewal Project., March 7, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Garage Price Estimate, Trenton Mall, City Center Urban Renewal Project., May 29, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, John Fitch Way #3, Urban Renewal Project Trenton., May 2, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Development Area A, John Fitch Way III, Urban Renewal Project., September 20, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Valuation, Sites Nos. 1 and 2, John Fitch Way III, Urban Renewal Project., October 9, 1968 (Box 1)
- Series II. Pennsylvania
  - Erie
    - Valuation Disposition Parcels, Erie Downtown., May 3, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcels, State Street, URP, Erie,., October 13, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Updated Valuations. Disposition Parcels, Erie Downtown., December 2, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Motel Site, TH-RO, Erie Downtown., January 30, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Updated Valuation Disposition Parcels, State Street, Erie., June 3, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Updated Valuation. Unsold Disposition Parcels, Downtown Erie., December 12, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Updated Valuation. Disposition Parcel 29-F, Downtown Erie Urban Renewal Project., April 30, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Philadelphia
    - Valuation Parcel 7, Market St., East Urban Renewal Project., September 1, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bethlehem
    - Valuation Re-Use Tracts A and B, Northhampton Heights Urban Renewal Project., September 1, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Reading
    - Valuation Planning and Market Analysis, Downtown East Urban Renewal Project., February 1, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Planning and Market Analysis, Downtown East Urban Renewal Project., February 1, 1968. (Box 1)
    - Valuation Market for Transient Housing, Downtown East Urban Renewal Project., February 2, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Lewistown
    - Land Utilization and Marketablity Study, East Market St., Urban Renewal Project., May 8, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Valuations Re-Use Parcels, East Market St., Urban Renewal Project., May 11, 1965 (Box 1)
- Series III. North Carolina
  - High Point
    - Acquisition Valuations, Elwood Hotel Property, East Central Urban Renewal Project, High Point., January 10, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Valuation, Magic Block 60, Parcel 1, East Central Urban Renewal Project., December 5, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Pilot Study Civic Center and Museum Project., October 13, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Report Elwood Hotel Property., March 1, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Market for Transient Housing, East Central Urban Renewal Project., May 16, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Recommendations and Findings Land Use and Marketability, Harrison Center Urban Renewal Project., August 5, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Charlotte
    - Re-Use Land Market, Brooklyn, Preliminary Report., November 5, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Re-Use Valuations, Land Utilization and Marketability Study, Brooklyn Section 1., October 1960 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Re-Use Parcels Section #1, Brooklyn., February 1, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Re-Use Parcels, Section #2, Brooklyn Neighborhood., March 5, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Re-Use Parcels, Section #3, Brooklyn., January 10, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Market for Transient Housing, Sections #3, 4, and 5, Brooklyn., June 1966 (Box 1)
    - Land Utilization and Market Study, Section #4, Brooklyn., October 5, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Land Utilization and Marketability Study, Sections #3, 4, and 5, Brooklyn., June 1966 (Box 1)
- Series IV. Missouri
  - St. Louis
    - Estimates of Values, Re-Use Parcels, Mill Creek Valley Redevelopment. (hard cover), October 21, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Estimates of Values, Re-Use Parcels, Mill Creek Valley (supplement), July 15, 1959. (Box 1)
    - Estimates of Values, Re-Use Parcels, Kosciusko., June 6, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Estimates of Values, Disposition Tracts Nos. 67, 69, 80 and 82, Mill Creek Valley., December 15, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Estimates of Values, Disposition of I-5, I-8, I-12, I-15, I-16, I-17, and I-19, Kosciusko., April 30, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Disposition Tracts 12A, 12B, 77 and 78, Mill Creek Valley Redevelopment., August 9, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Re-Use Valuations, Industrial Tracts 36A, 36B, 59A, 59B, Commercial Tracts 83, 84, and 38, Mill Creek Valley., March 13, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Valuations Disposition Tracts 68, 77A, 78B and 79, Mill Creek Valley., October 1, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Industrial Dispositions Tracts, Kosciusko., October 2, 1963 (Box 1)
- Series V. New Mexico
  - Los Alamos
    - Examination of FHA Procedures, Pricing of Disposal Properties, Los Alamos., April 30, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Commercial Properties, Los Alamos., December 22, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Community Center, Los Alamos., August 21, 1967 (Box 1)
- Series VI. Nevada
  - Nevada Community
    - Report to U.S. Atomic Energy Commission Financial Plan for Nevada Community., December 1, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Report to U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Alternate Finance Plan for Nevada Housing., March 4, 1963 (Box 1)
- Series VII. Virginia
  - Reston
    - Valuation Real Estate Properties, Reston., December 1967 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Real Estate Properties, Reston, and itemized properties., December 1967 (Box 1)
  - Fairfax
    - Valuation, Burling Tract, Fairfax County., May 1, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Danville
    - Survey of Re-Use Market, Union St., Redevelopment., October 15, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Estimates of Values, Re-Use Parcels, Union St., December 15, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Revaluation of Re-Use Parcels, Union St., January 1964 (Box 1)
    - Valuation of Re-Use Parcels, Block A,C,D,E, and F., December 21, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Ridge Street Redevelopment, Danville. (hard cover), July 15, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Dulles
    - Valuations, Development Sites in C-7 Office Bldg., Area Dulles 1A., August 2, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Newport News
    - Central District Redevelopment, Newport News., January 31, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Valuations, Disposition Tracts 2A, 2B, 9, 12, 14, 16, 17B, 17C, 18 and 19., January 1961 (Box 1)
  - Alexandria
    - Redevelopment Parcel A, Phase II, Gadsby., April 1968 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel D, Gadsby Commercial Urban Renewal., June 1969 (Box 1)
    - Valuations Disposition Parcels B and C, Gadsby Commercial., January 1970 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcels, B.C.D. Gadsby Commercial., September 7, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Arlington
    - Hot Shoppes Drive-In Restaurant, S Approaches 14th St., July 1959 (Box 1)
  - Norfolk
    - Valuations Leasehold Estate and Equity, Little Creek Apartments, Title VIII., January 10, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Valuation Parcels 31 and 32, Atlantic City Redevelopment., September 17, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Estimate of Damage to Norfolk Southern Railway Co., Jan 6, 1969 (Box 1)
- Series VIII. Kansas
  - Fort Leavenworth
    - Leasehold Estates and Equities Kent Homes, Marshall Homes, Title VIII., March 17, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Fort Riley
    - Valuations Leasehold Estate and Equity, Fort Riley Apartments, Title VIII Housing Project., March 11, 1958 (Box 1)
- Series IX. Illinois
  - Rantoul
    - Valuations Leasehold Estates and Equities, Chanute Apartments, Chanute Gardens, Title VIII, Chanute Air Force Base, Rantoul, Illinois., May 1, 1957 (Box 2)
- Series X. New York
  - New York City
    - Research Proposal Movable School Structures., November 1, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Utica
    - Central District Redevelopment, Utica, New York., January 15, 1957 (Box 2)
- Series XI. Indiana
  - South Bend
    - Valuations, Disposition Parcels, Chapin St., Urban Renewal Project., July 7, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Valuations Disposition Parcels, La Salle Park Urban Renewal Project, South Bend., December 10, 1965 (Box 2)
- Series XII. Iowa
  - Dubuque
    - Housing in Dubuque., August 19, 1946 (Box 2)
- Series XIII. Minnesota
    - Housing in Minnesota, January 15, 1941 (Box 2)
- Series XIV. Washington, D.C.
    - Preliminary Acquisition Cost Estimates, First Project Area, D.C. Redevelopment Land Agency. (hard cover), September 19, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Wholesale Food Market, Southwest Redevelopment, D.C., May 25, 1955 (Box 2)
    - Farmers Produce Market., August 30, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Municipal Fish Market and Wharf, Southwest Redevelopment., August 30, 1957 (Box 2)
    - Valuations Waterfront Disposition Sites., September 24, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Re-Use Valuation Site E, Waterfront Redevelopment., April 14, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Valuations Waterfront Disposition Sites., December 28, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Valuations Site F, Pier 4, and Site P-6, Southwest Redevelopment., July 21, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Zoning, Mount Vernon Square East., October 1972 (Box 2)
    - Valuation 4880 MacArthur Blvd., October 1972 (Box 2)
    - Valuations, Waterfront Disposition Sites D-1, D-2, A & D-2, & D-2-B, Southwest Redevelopment Project., December 2, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Waterfront Disposition Site C-3, 6, Southwest Redevelopment., July 15, 1977 (Box 2)
- Series XV. Maryland
  - Baltimore
    - Valuation Baltimore Dairy Plant plus correspondence., May 26, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 7, Charles Center., December 1959 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 13, Charles Center., December 1959 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 5, Charles Center., March 1960 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 6, Charles Center., July 1960 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 9, 10, 11, Charles Center., July 1960 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 2, Charles Center., July 1960 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 3, Charles Center., July 1960 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 12A and 12B, Charles Center., January 1961 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 8A and 8B, Charles Center., April 1961 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 4, Charles Center., August 1961 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 15, Charles Center., December 1961 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 9, 10, 11, Charles Center., March 1962 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 1 and 2, Charles Center., June 1962 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 14, Charles Center., June 1962 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 16A, Charles Center., September 1964 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 1 and 2, Charles Center., September 1964 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 3A, Charles Center., December 1964 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 12, Charles Center., January 1965 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 6, Charles Center., February 1965 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 5, Charles Center., July 1966 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 16B, Charles Center., November 1966 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 1, Inner Harbor Project I., July 10, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 18, Inner Harbor Project I., November 21, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Reevaluation Remaining Property, Charles Center Development Area 9, 10, 11., April 1969 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 4, Inner Harbor., December 10, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 8-9, Inner Harbor Project I. (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 15C, Inner Harbor Project I., May 1, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 15A, 22, 23, Inner Harbor Project I., April 1971 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 5, Inner Harbor Project I., July 31, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 9A, Inner Harbor Project I., April 27, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 11, Inner Harbor Project I., December 5, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 5, Charles Center, Baltimore., March 20, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 15A, 22 and 23, Inner Harbor Project I., November 8, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 25, Inner Harbor., July 18, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Area 5A, Inner Harbor West., July 18, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Development Areas 16A and 17A, Inner Harbor West., October 7, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Montgomery County
    - Review of Re-Use Appraisals, Emory Grove Project in Montgomery County., December 29, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Red Gate Farm Industrial Land, Rockville., March 9, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Reduction in Value, No. 5 Bay Tree Lane, Lot 9, Tulip Hill (Box 2)
  - Rockville
    - Valuation Disposition Tracts Mid-City Urban Renewal., May 16, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Tract D-8, Mid-City., September 17, 1965 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Parcel 2B, Mid-City., November 7, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Tracts 3A, Mid-City., November 7, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Tracts, Junior College Urban Renewal., December 11, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 1-C, Mid-City., June 1969 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 1-D, Mid-City., July 1970 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 2E, Mid-City., July 1970 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Parcel 2B-1. Mid-City., February 1971 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 2E, Mid-City., February 1971 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 4A, Mid-City., April 1971 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 2C, Mid-City., September 19, 1973. (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 2D, Mid-City., September 1973. (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcel 3C, Mid-City., October 1973. (Box 2)
  - Cumberland
    - Urban Renewal Plan Center City II, Urban Renewal Area., May 26, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Valuation Disposition Parcels, George Street Urban Renewal Project., February 23, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Valuations Disposition Parcels, George St., Urban Renewal Project, Cumberland., February 28, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Laurel
    - Valuation Kimco Maryland, Inc. Zayre Store, Laurel. (Copy I to Wyoming has correspondence file), August 4, 1971 (Box 2)
- Series XVI. Miscellaneous Reports
    - War Housing Proposal., July 1942 (Box 3)
    - Toward a Postwar Housing Program prepared for Postwar Committee and the Producer's Council., May 1, 1944 (Box 3)
    - Report on Interest Rate for G.I. Home Loans. Prepared for Organizations Council of Altadena, California, Fall., 1948 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations on Air Force Housing Legislation., March 1, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations and Suggestions on Policies and Practices in Housing of Families of Government Workers for Bureau of Budget., June 1, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Preliminary Suggestions on NSRB Planning Project Housing and Community Facilities in Post-Attack Industrial Rehabilitation., December 27, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Discussion of Methods of Determining Values and Time Charter Hire Rates of Requisitional Vessels. A Report to American-Hawaiian Steamship Co., June 25, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Methods of Valuation and Estimation of Hire Rates of Requisitioned Ships. Report to American-Hawaiian Steamship Co., August 22, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations on Private Rental Housing Legislation for Oak Ridge and Richland., February 27, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Recommendations on Private Rental Housing Legislation for Oak Ridge and Richland., August 9, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Report on Current Status of Plans of the Federal Security Agency on Housing and Community Facilities in Post-Attack Industrial Rehabilitation., April 8, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Report to Home Builders on Recommended Appraisal Research., December 14, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Report on Recommended NAHB Activities in Appraisal Field, prepared for NAHB., December 15, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Report Training Curriculum, FHA Multiple Housing Programs., December 6, 1961 (Box 3)
    - Quality Rating of Mortgage Portfolios to Board of Governors, Federal Reserve System., September 15, 1964 (Box 3)
    - Land Acquisition Procedures and Techniques., July 30, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Valuation Processing in New Communities Program, Department of HUD., September 6, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Disposition Practices, Organization and Procedures., February 1973 (Box 3)
    - Re-Use Valuation Techniques, Principles and Processes, A Report for D.C., R.L.A., February 1973 (Box 3)
    - Instructions for Land Acquisition Appraisers., March 1973 (Box 3)
    - 11th Annual Report of FHA., 1944 (Box 3)
    - Report: Trend in Section 50I GI Home Loan Activity. (Box 3)